Guide to the Stanford Universtiy, Center for Ethics in Society, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Universtiy, Center for Ethics in Society, records
undated
SC1220
Stanford Universtiy. Center for Ethics in Society.
10 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - 420/041 Master Philosophy 2:15 p.m., 2001 Jan. 26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Veillon/The Carpet 1.) The Carpet: 6:48 2.) "La March du Siecle": 2:40; Lynn Paine RT: 9:28 MS#5231, 1998 Aug. 31; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Life of the Mind Moral Medicine, 1998 May; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tanner Lectures: Dorothy Allison Kresge Auditorium/ Stanford Univ., 2001 May 15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Quine Mem. Tape #2 420/041, 2001 Jan. 26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Colorblind?" (18 min., 2004) Ian Slatterly Sociology/Ethics in Society, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tape #1 420/041 2:15 p.m., 2001 Jan. 26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Quine Mem. Videos Tape #2 420/041, 2001 Jan. 26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Life of the Mind Cultivating Distrust: The Development of Three Cultures of Democracy in America, 1999 Feb. 8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Life of the Mind Cultivating Distrust: The Development of Three Cultures of Democracy in America, 1999 Feb. 8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The 59 Story Crisis: A Lesson in Professional Behavior William J. LeMessurier, 1995 Nov. 17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Life of the Mind Tanner Lectures in Human Values, 2001 Part 2: What it Means to Be Free (Dorothy Allison), 2001 May 15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Life of the Mind Tanner Lectures in human Values, 2001 Part 1: Mean Stories and Stubborn Girls (Dorothy Allison), 2001 May 14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Life of the Mind: Modern Lessons from Ecological Collapses of Ancient Civilizations, 2000 May 22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Life of the Mind: Modern Lessons from Ecological Collapses of Ancient Civilizations, 2000 May 22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Life of the Mind: Modern Lessons from Ecological Collapses of Ancient Civilizations, 2000 May 22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Life of the Mind Democracy and Social Justice: Democracy and Human Rights (Sen), 2001 Jan. 15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Life of the Mind Deocracy and Social Justice: Limits of Contractual Reasoning (Sen), 2001 Jan. 15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Life of the Mind Deocracy and Social Justice: Limits of Contractual Reasoning (Sen), 2001 Jan. 16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Life of the Mind Deocracy and Social Justice: Limits of Contractual Reasoning (Sen), 2001 Jan. 17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Our Obligations to Outsiders: Obligations Beyond the Species Boundary Part 2, 2000 May 16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Our Obligations to Outsiders: Obligations Beyond the Species Boundary Part 2, 2000 May 16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Our Obligations to Outsiders: Obligation Beyond National Borders Part 1, 2000 May 16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dorothy Allison - Kresge Aud. 5p-7p, 2001 April 14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Judge Posner Philosphy Dept. Kresge Aud. Job #35153 5-7 p.m., 2001 Nov. 14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Amartye Sen Wesson Lectures, 2001 Jan.; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Wesson Lecture Noam Chomsky, 1994 April 6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Paul Krugman, Currency Crises, 2002 March 19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Judge Richard Posner Kresge Auditorium Job # 35153-2 5-7 PM, 2001 Nov. 15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Nicole Sanchez Associate Director Program in Ethics in Society, 2003 July; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Master Philosphy 420/041 2:15 PM, 2001 Jan. 26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Struggle for Moral Leadership Public Virtues, Private Lives, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Sturggle for Moral Leadership Integrity and Compromise, circa 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Wesson Lectures Life of the Mind The Age of Civil War and Emancipation 2 of 2, 1997 April; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Wesson Lectures Life of the Mind The American Revolution and Its legacy 1 of 2, 1997 April; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Life of the Mind: When Do Green Values Pay Off for Big Businesses?, 2000 May 23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Life of the Mind: When Do Green Values Pay Off for Big Businesses?, 2000 May 23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Life of the Mind: When Do Green Values Pay Off for Big Businesses?, 2000 May 23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Life of the Mind Trust and Democratic transition in Contemporary America with Orlando Patterson, 1999 Feb. 9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Title IX Tape #1, undated; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Title IX Tape #2, undated; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Title IX Tape #3, undated; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Title IX Tape #4, undated; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Title IX Tape #5, undated; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - EIS Lecture Series Paul Ehrlich: "The Value of Biodiversity", 1991 Feb. 8; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Richard Kahlenberg Diverse Approaches to Affirmative Action, 2003 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Unlabeled Sony audicassette, undated; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agrueszka Jaworska, 2000 May 12; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harsanyi "Equality, Responsibilty, & Justice", (unknown year) May 11; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tanner Lecture - Krugman Bishop Aud. Tape #1, 2002 March 18; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 200/107 3-5:15 pm Tape 2-2, 2002 May 17; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - EthicsSoc Noon Tom Sheeran, 2000 Feb. 13; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - EIS Sissela Bok "Ethics + Professional Resp.", 1992 Jan. 17; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ethics @ Noon Steve Macedo, 2000 April 21; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Prof. Amartya Sen Kresge Aud., 2001 Jan. 15; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Richard A. Posner (#1), 2001 Nov. 15; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Richard A. Posner (#2), 2001 Nov. 14; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - A. Prof. Richard Porty; B. Mary Porty, 2000 May 26; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Richard A. Posner Kresge Auditorium (#1), 2001 Nov. 14; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Danny kahnman Arrow Lecture Psychology & Economics, 1999 April 20; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bernard Williams, 1990 Jan. 26; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1990 Wesson Lecture; Albert hirschman "200 years of Reactionary Rhetoric: The Futility Thesis", 1990 Feb. 12; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ethics @ Noon Al Camarillo Sheltering the Homeless: Ethical Dimensions for Non-Profit Organizations and their Supporters, 2000 March 3; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bill Morning Corporate Ethics, 2001 Feb. 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Prof. John Manley Webb Ranch, 2000 March 31; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Paul Ehrlich, 2001 May 11; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Unlabeled Scotch Audiocassette, undated; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Kresge Aud., 2003 Feb. 13; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Paul Krugman, Currency Crises, 2002 March 19; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ethics @ Noon A. Akhil Gupta, B. David Luban, 2000 April 7, 14; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Unlabeled D90 Auidocassette, undated; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Q&A Afternoon/ Diverse Approaches to Affirmative Action, 2003 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Prof. Amartya Sen, 2001 Jan. 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ostrom Tape 2, 2010 April 8; 1 videotape(s) (miniDV) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jeffrey Sachs, 2010 Feb. 18; 1 videotape(s) (miniDV) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mobile Healthy #2, 2012 May 17; 1 videotape(s) (miniDV) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Bernard Williams Wesson Lecture, 1991; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Prof. Bernard Williams Wesson Lecture Kresge Aud. Side A & B, 1991 April 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Wesson Lecture Stephen Solarz, 1993; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Diverse Approaches to Affirmative Action/ Q&A (morning), 2003 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Rev. Scotty McLennan Moral Risk Factors in Business Land Life, undated; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bernard Williams Wesson, 1991 April 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Loury (2) Pamela Karla (1 0f 2) / Diverse Approaches to Affirmative Action, 2003 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - EIS Lecture, R. hardin "The Costs and Benefits of Future Generations", 1991 May 10; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 1/2 Lecture only Ethics, L. Blum "Multiculuralism, Anti-Racism as Moral Education", (unknown year) April 20; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Philosphy M 200/107 Tape 1-2, 2002 May 17; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - T.N. Srimvasan, 2001 April 20; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Prof. Amartya Sen., 2001 Jan. 15; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Liz Anderseon/ Diverse Approaches to Affirmative Action, 2003 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - EiS Lecture Series "Facts & values in Environmental Policy Formation" Ken Arrow, 1991 March 1; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - S-2 Berry #530 Prime, 2011 Nov. 22; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Stanford University 300/300 Tape Two, 2002 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Stanford University 300/300 Tape One Side A/ Side B, 2002 May 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Tanner Mary Robinson/Kresge Aud. Stanford #I, 2003 Feb. 12; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - 200/2003 #1 7-9 pm / Panel - Athletics/Nike #1, 2001 April 26; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Prof. Amartya Sen 2 Kresge Aud., 2001 Jan. 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - A. Roger Noll, Economics, 2000 June 2; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Rabbi Patricia Kartin - Neumann Face @12, 2000 Nov. 16; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Ethics @ Noon Susan Okin: Women's Rights As Human Rights", 2000 Feb. 11; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Ethics @ Noon: Stephen Zipperstein, 2000 Feb. 25; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Athletics + Nike Contract 200/2003 #2, 2001 April 26; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - 2002 Kant Lecture: Philip Kitcher; Stanford/ note: presenter declined to wear lapel mic provided, 2002 May 15; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Richard A. Posner (#2), 2001 Nov. 15; 1 audicassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Press Clippings, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Buzz McCoy Materials, 1983-2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mellon Sawyer Proposal Integrating Moral Theory & Practice for 05-06, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Random Event Flyers Early 2000's, 1998-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 2001-2002 Thesis Fall Presentations (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - More EIS Honors (2006 & 2007) Honors Presentation Announcements + '92-'94 EIS Graduates Bios (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Honors Program 1992-95-ish + Some Stanford Daily Articles, 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2006-2007 Major Activities (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 2007-08 Preliminary Calendar of Events, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Doping in Sports (Events) Jan 17, 2008, 2008 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Other" Events 2001-2007 incl: Charter Schools Everyday Ethics (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Ethics of Cloning Companion Animals" May 12, 2000, 2000 April-May (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 2005 Event Terry Schiavo, 2005 March-April (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Torture Conf., 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Moral Responsibilty Lectures 4/13, 4/20, 5/01 - 2000, 2000 April-May (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - John Rawls 1986-87 Wesson, 1986 Oct.-Nov, April (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ethics @ Noon 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Women's Issues Events, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Susan Okin Conference Materials Feb. 2005, 2005 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - War Series Ads 2010, 2010 Oct.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1998-8 EIS Talks/Lectures, 1996-1998, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - EIS Lectures 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Tomasello Newspaper Ads + Articles 2008, 2008 Oct.-Nov. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Misc Event Posters lates '80's - 2000's Ethics @ Noon; Everyday Ethics; & More, 1989-2007 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Inter-Action & Stanford Daily Articles on Career Initiations 2005 + 2008 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cosmopolitanism & Nationalism Conf. April 15-17, 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1999 Invitations & Thank Yous to Participants in Cosmopoltanism + Nationalism Conference, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Ethics in Society Conference '97, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - The American Legal Profession March 14, 2008 Conference, 2008 March (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Symposium on Civic Engagement & Graduate Education 2006, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Photos John Manley Ethics @ Noon, 2000, Photographs (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - New Directions for Corporate Government [Co-Sponsored] 2008, 2008 Feb. 9 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Publicity 2005 Moral Leadership Conference, 2005 March (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Start of Wesson Lectures, 1985, through 91 (Death of Bob Wesson), 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Ethics & the Professions Class, Spring 2002 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1992-1996 Event Flyers for EIS Lectures (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Everyday Ethics - Sports, Ethics Events, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 2002: "Inequality & Indignation" (Edna Ellmann - Margalit) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - 2006: Actor's Gang (Residency, Workshop for Hope House Women, Performance of "The Exonerated" (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Stress & Cheating 2006 &: Ethics, Politics, and Housing (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Spring 2007 Events, 2007 Feb. - May (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Josh Korn Bluth Event March 9, 2007 "Love & Taxes", 2007 March (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Paul Longmore (Disabilty Rights) 2005, 2005 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Equality & Markets Sept. 06 Conference, 2006 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Misc: 2005-2006 Co-Sponsored Events (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 2001 Event Proposal on Ethics of Relationship btw. Stanford Athletics + Corporate Sponsors, 2001 April (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Dan Hoyle - Circumnavigator, 2004 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Example Welcome Folder 2008 Event, 2008 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Invitations to 2001 "Integrating Moral Theory & Moral Practice" Conference, 2000 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Global Justice 2005 Workshop Proposal Acceptance, 2005 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Policy Board, 2005 Jan. 21 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Syllabi - Stanford Ann Mongovan, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - External Advisory/ Board Members, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - 2007 Wkshop proposal: Heritage Ethics, 2007 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 2001 - Student Aartni Belani's Notes from Ethics @ Noon Events, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Arthur Applbaum 2000 Moral Responsibilty in Real World Contexts, 2000 Jan.-May (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Steve Macedo 2000 Moral Responsibily in Real World Contexts, 2000 Feb.-April; 2 photographs (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - David Luban 2000 Moral Responsibility in Real World Contexts, 2000 Feb. - April (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Example Packet for Undergrad Applicants to the Honors Program (2007), 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Assoc. Dir. Job Dec. '03 Ad Job Posting 2003, 2003 Dec. 10 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Assoc. Director, Ethics Ad Job Posting, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Name Plates, etc. Wesson Lecture 2001 Richard Posner, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Wesson 1987 Judith Shklar Invited, 1987 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Wesson 1990 Bernard Williams, 1991 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Lyle Cook Memorial, 2002 May (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ethics in Society Visiting Scholar 1994, 1993 Dec. - 1994 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - 1992-3 Visiting Scholar Prof. S. Warqar Ahmed Husaini, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - China Papers Anne Mangouan's Book Reviews of Books about China, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Center Brochure 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - 2004 Honors Program Newsletter, 2004 April (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Center Brochure 2012-13, 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Etyhics Center Brochrues 2013-14 Brochures for Undergrad Honors Ogrm. + Center for Ethics, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Spring 2014 Events Bookmark (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - 25th Snniv. Booklet Created by Communications Associate Lily Bixler Clausen in 2013 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Newsletters 1998-2011 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Tanner Lectures, 1989-2013 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arrow lectures, 2005-2013 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ethics at noon, 0 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wesson lectures, 1986-2013 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ethics in Society events, 1980-2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Posters, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Postcards and event materials, 2006-2014 (Box 4)
- Posters (Box 5-6)